Adriana Valdiglesias

(860) 458-8064 | adrianavaldiglesias2@gmail.com | West Hartford, CT 06110

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/2QSndJ8 | Github: https://bit.ly/3upRc9B | Portfolio: https://bit.ly/2QVeQMU

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate Full Stack Software Engineer leveraging a background in customer services. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly web applications. Proactive self-starter dedicated to continued learning. Experience developing software independently and in a team setting. Dedicated contributor recognized for effective communication and organization abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js (hooks, router, & context API), Redux(Saga & Forms), JSX, GIT, GitHub, NoSQL and SQL databases (MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Firestore), Next.js, Figma, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, Material UI, GatsbyJS, REST APIs, AWS, Authentication (Bcrypt, Session, JWTs), Heroku, Terminal, AJAX, Restful API, ES6, JSON, Seguelize, Firebase, TDD

EDUCATION

Full Stack Engineering Program - University of Connecticut | 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills

35 credit hours towards an Associate of Science in Psychology - Manchester Community College

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Known Point Technologies | West Hartford, CT (Remote) *Frontend Software Engineer*

04/2021 - Present

- Contributes to website by implementing React.js, Redux, and Bootstrap CSS elements (flexbox & grid) to create "squishy" designs that remained responsive across all device instances
- Meets with the UX/UI, Product, and Engineering teams utilizing an agile mindset for delivering, sustaining, and discussing the product roadmap with CTO
- Produce, maintain and modify website and user interface. Create tools that enhance user experience
- Routinely tests website and organizes bug bash sessions to test new releases for speed, performance and usability. Adding any issues or bugs that arise onto the roadmap in a Kanban format

OPEN SOURCE

TakeOff Application | Deployed Application: https://bit.ly/3b5WMGC | Github: https://bit.ly/3nRf5V0

- Creates the application with Material UI, applied dark-mode to reduce user eye strain
- Manages and designs with Adobe typekit to support local typographers
- Utilizes React Hooks to coordinate user flows without compromising scalability or efficiency

No-Waste-Kitchen | Deployed Application: https://bit.ly/3vRYtiD | Github: https://bit.ly/3vEfHjA

- Ensure a responsive web design using Bootstrap and Skeleton CSS Frameworks
- Incorporated Javascript APIs for client side storage of application data to render persistent data
- Provided creative vision and concept design for logo and wireframe. Developed mockups per wireframe

WORK EXPERIENCE

Porron & Pina; Hartford, CT *Food Runner*

08/2018 - 03/2020

 Demonstrated leadership abilities by working diligently to increase customer satisfaction through managing expectations and strong interpersonal communication